Now let's cover the ITTOs of developing
the project management plan.
That would be on page 82 of your PIMBuck.
All right, so this process, based on the
high level information we have in the
project charter, we will figure out all
the details.
All right, so we'll define, prepare,
and coordinate all plan components and
consolidate them into an integrated
project management plan.
So progressive elaboration is key here.
We have to start somewhere.
So think of developed the project
management plan as the border of a puzzle.
We're starting.
All right.
So we're going to figure out our approach,
strategy, methodology
that we're going to use.
That's planning.
All right.
So we will define.
prepare, coordinate all plan components.
So again, develop the project management
plan is the first process where we will
start our puzzle, starting with the
border.
All right, so our inputs, the project
charter.
We did create that.
We just discussed it when we develop the
project charter process in initiating.
So that contains all our high level
information in it.
High level requirements, summary budgets,
summary schedule, any stakeholders we know
about, any key stakeholders
we know about, any
risks we know about,
high level project objectives.
Now we're going to figure out the details.
We see the second input, outputs from
other processes.
Well, these are mainly planning processes.
So again, we're starting right now to
develop the project management plan.
Then we're going to go through our other
knowledge areas.
Again, you can refer to page 25 in your
Pimbach.
So we will plan each of the
other knowledge areas and
create pieces of the puzzle
called subsidiary plans.
So that's why you must understand
progressive elaboration.
We have to start somewhere.
Then we'll move into
another process, uncover
more details, go back
and update what we started.
So just think we're
going to have a planning
meeting and we'll plan
all the pieces of our puzzle.
Then you have those EEFs and OPAs again.
You can see you can run but you can't
hide.
They impact us.
So throughout integration and our planning
processes, we see them
over and over and over.
Tools and techniques.
Remember, these are verbs.
We use expert judgment again.
Ours, our team members are SMEs,
brains, experience and expertise.
We'll gather data again.
So now, again, we're trying to figure out
our best approach strategy to planning,
to take our project from beginning to end.
So we'll do brainstorming again.
You can use checklists.
Those are OPAs, making sure steps are
being followed.
Focus groups, just like we talked about
and developed the project charter,
pre-qualified SMEs, and we're going to
interview our key stakeholders.
Because we're dealing with stakeholders,
we'll use those interpersonal team skills.
Remember, those are your soft skills.
So again, we're going to manage conflict.
Not everybody's going to agree.
We'll facilitate the meetings,
come to a conclusion.
As we manage meetings, having meetings.
So these look familiar.
We'll see a lot of the, and use a lot of
the same tools and
techniques over and over.
All right, what is the output?
Remember, inputs and outputs are nouns,
artifacts.
inputs what's the information we need
outputs what are we creating so the
process is develop the project management
plan so what do we produce every time we
plan a plan the project management plan
and it is considered the most important
project document which will
tell us how and provide guidance
on how we will take our
project from beginning to end